

Soma Utsumi

Site Reliability Engineer

- Tokyo, Japan
- qithub.com/soma00333
- soma00333.notion.site/Soma-Utsumi-32fff212315a4e9d894b704d52b23074

SUMMARY

Senior Software Engineer with 6+ years and Site Reliability Engineer with 2+ years professional experience in Japan.

Engaged in the backend developments for enterprise SaaS and the design and operation of cloud infrastructures with high-security requirements.

SKILLS

SRE

- SLI/SLO Design
- Postmortem
- Kubernetes
- Datadog
- Terraform
- GCP
- AWS

Backend

- Go
- gRPC
- MySQL

LANGUAGES

- Japanese(Native)
- English(Professional working)

WORK EXPERIENCE

2024-04 - Side, SRE in AI • LLM Division

Present LayerX Inc.

2023-11 - Side, SRE in SRE desk

Present enechain Corporation

- Lead creating manifest and terraform generator tools for developers that accelerate microservice development.
- Maintain and operate infrastructures centered on GKE.
- Lead rebuilding teams and policies for RBAC, service account, IAM, and tools like GitHub. Focus on governance and security.

2019-04 - **CTO**

Present Industry Technology Inc.

- Lead the backend development of enterprise SaaS with Go and gRPC.
- Lead the creation of application infrastructures with AWS and Terraform.
- Lead migrating legacy Aurora Serverless v1 (MySQL 5.7) to Aurora Serverless v2 (MySQL v8.0) without downtime.
- Lead getting logs and metrics, designing SLI/SLO, and setting appropriate dashboards and monitors on Datadoq.

2023-08 - Side, Infra Engineer in LLM STUDIO

2024-04 Algomatic Inc.

- Lead the creation of learning infrastructures for LLM with AWS.
- Lead the creation of inference servers for LLM with AWS.
- Lead the creation of infrastructures for LLM applications with AWS.

2018-04 - Data Analyst, Digital Marketer

2019-06 Gunosy Inc.

- Lead planning and applying A/B tests. Increase user retention by 30%.
- Analyze the large-scale user data with MySQL and Redshift

2018-01 - Intern, Backend Engineer

2018-03 ZUU Co.,Ltd.

• Develop the internal system with Go

EDUCATION

2014 - 2018 Bachelor of Engineering

The University of Tokyo

Design of a preoperative evaluation system for elderly patients using a generalized linear model